Perkins, J. Greg mss. 1981-2018 LMC 2890
Lilly Library
Perkins, J. Greg mss.
1981-2022
2018
Lilly Library
Perkins, J. Greg, 1945-
LMC 2890
6 Boxes
1 folio oversize
The Perkins, J. Greg Mss., ca. 1981-2018 consists of manuscripts, revision-related correspondence, and final versions of plays, novels, and short stories, as well as scholarly writings and professional papers of Dr. J. Greg Perkins, author.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
J. Greg Perkins (1945-) was born in Kokomo, Indiana. He is the author of the Darkness Before Mourning series, which will total 19 volumes upon its complete publication. Published works from the series include The Announcers (2015) and Harvest of Ashes (2017). His writing provides a window into life in 1950s America.
Dr. Perkins received his B.S. in chemistry and a Ph.D. in biochemistry from Indiana University. With over 30 years in the pharmaceutical industry, he has been a senior executive at Solvay Pharmaceuticals, Hoffman-LaRoche, and Burroughs Wellcome. Perkins has written numerous New Drug Applications (NDAs), Investigational New Drug Applications (INDs) and scientific papers, and also is co-author of Pharmaceutical Marketing: Principles, Environment, and Practice (2002).
Throughout his professional career, Dr. Perkins wrote fiction on the side, never intending for anyone else to read his works until 2012 when he began to adapt part of his work for a play. It was while working on the script that his work was discovered, and subsequently published as the Darkness Before Mourning series, by Chatwin Books. He currently resides in Seattle.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series: I. Writings II. Scholarship III. Solvay Pharmaceuticals, and IV. 2022 Additions.
Scope and Content Note
Collection acquired with books: one hard-bound and one paperback copy of The Announcers and one hard-bound and one paperback copy of Harvest of Ashes, as well as a hard-bound copy of Perkins' dissertation, Optical Properties of Rat Brain Myelin and Binding Properties and Partial Characterization of Proteolipids Isolated from the Central Nervous System.
The "Scholarship" series also includes related correspondence and copies of source materials not authored by Perkins.
Correspondents include Amanda Knox, editor. The 2022 Additions consist of word-processed drafts of Perkins' books Cancer Offering, The Caring Profession, Frozen Sunrise, A Candle Flickers, and Encircled by Vultures.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 2018
biochemistry; Pharmaceutical chemistry; Perkins, J. Greg, 1945-
- Writings (Box 1)
  - "The Carrot" (1981) (Box 1)
  - The Pork Chop/December Fourth Early Draft, 3 Folders (Box 1)
  - The Pork Chop/December Fourth 2015 Draft, 3 Folders (Box 1)
  - The Pork Chop/December Fourth 2018 Draft, 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - The Cosmic Idiot 2017 Draft (Box 1)
  - Three Missing Fathers First Draft (Box 1)
  - Three Missing Fathers Second Draft (Box 1)
  - Three Missing Fathers Third Draft (2018), 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - A Harvest of Ashes Third Draft (2015), 3 Folders (Box 2)
  - A Harvest of Ashes Third Draft (2015) Correspondence, Revisions, Notes (Box 2)
  - "Zelda and Dorothy at the Pearly Gates" (2013), 4 Folders (Box 2)
  - "Zelda and Dorothy at the Pearly Gates" (2013) Fragment (Box 2)
- Scholarship
  - Witkacy 2009
    - Conference-Related Materials (Box 2)
    - "Eluding the Void" Presentation (Box 2)
  - "Samuel Beckett and Philosophy" (2014) (Box 2)
- Solvay Pharmaceuticals
  - QA/QC Compliance & Staffing Report (1996) (Box 2)
  - Global Regulatory Systems (2000) (Box 2)
  - Job Descriptions (2001) (Box 2)
- 2022 Additions
  - Cancer Offering (Box 3)
    - Cancer Story, 4/15/08; 3 Folders (Box 3)
    - Path Descendant, 3 Folders (Box 3)
    - A Path Descending, 11/25/20; 2 Folders (Box 3)
    - Cancer Offering, 5/14/21; 2 Folders (Box 3)
  - The Caring Profession (Box 4)
    - The Far Side of Evisceration, 3 Folders (Box 4)
    - The Caring Profession, 2/25/21; 2 Folders (Box 4)
  - Frozen Sunrise (Box 4)
    - Slipperiest of Slopes, 3/20/09; 3 Folders (Box 4)
    - Frozen Sunrise, 8/7/21; 2 Folders (Box 4)
  - A Candle Flickers (Box 4)
    - Diary entries (Box 4)
    - Draft, 10/20/21; 2 Folders (Box 4)
  - Encircled by Vultures (Box 4)
    - Diary entries (Box 4)
    - Draft, 1/25/22; 2 Folders (Box 4)
  - Signed Writing as Memory poster for Harvest of Ashes (Ovflat 37)
  - Darkest of Darks, undated (Box 5)
    - Volume I pp.1-31, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Volume I pp.32-62, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Volume I pp.63-93, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Volume I pp.94-124, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Volume I pp.125-155, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Volume I pp.156-186, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Volume I pp.187-200, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Volume I Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Volume II pp.201-231, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Volume II pp.232-262, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Volume II pp.263-293, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Volume II pp.294-324, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Volume II pp.325-355, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Volume II pp.356-386, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Volume II pp.387-400, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Volume II Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Volume III pp.401-431, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Volume III pp.432-462, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Volume III pp.463-493, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Volume III pp.494-524, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Volume III pp.525-555, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Volume III pp.556-586, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Volume III pp.587-607, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Volume III Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Volume IV pp.609-639, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Volume IV pp.640-670, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Volume IV pp.672-702, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Volume IV pp.703-733, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Volume IV pp.734-764, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Volume IV pp.765-800, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Volume IV Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Volume V pp.801-831, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Volume V pp.832-862, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Volume V pp.863-902, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Volume V Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - A Candle Flickers, 20 October 2021 (Box 5)
    - Addendum, 20 October 2021 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - A Candle Extinguishing, 07 April 2022 (Box 5)
    - pp.1-31, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - pp.32-62, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - pp.63-93, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - pp.94-124, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - pp.125-155, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - pp.156-182, 07 April 2022 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - A Candle Extinguished, 02 June 2022 (Box 5)
    - pp.1-31, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - pp.32-62, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - pp.63-93, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - pp.94-124, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - pp.125-155, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - pp.156-186, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - pp.187-217, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - pp.218-238, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - pp.239-259, 02 June 2022 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Aftermath, 04 August 2022 (Box 5)
    - pp.1-31, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - pp.32-62, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - pp.63-93, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - pp.94-124, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - pp.125-145, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - pp.146-168, 04 August 2022 (Box 5, Folder 57)
- 2023 Additions
  - Inventory to accruals, 7/28/23 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Emails with Lindsay Hill regarding original draft of Desultory Scribblings (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Desultory Scribblings draft (including chapters moved to Aftermath)
    - Chapters 1-12 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Chapters 13-20 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Chapters 21-26 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Desultory Scribblings draft, 10/2/22
    - Chapters 1-15 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 16-29 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Electromagnetism and the Tornado" + photocopies of Bernard Vonnegut correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)